Sourav Saha

Personal Information

Bangalore, India souravsaha1605@gmail.com

8981782777 - Portfolio - LinkedIn Live Resume - Kaggle

Career Summary

4 years of professional work experience on Natural Language processing, Data Science and Data Structure. Proposed multiple business solutions to stakeholders as a part of job role and helped developing solution for them. Mentored more than 30 interns with skills on Machine Learning, Website Development, Design, HR and Content Writing for my hobby project - Personalized Email Digest and Google Search Recommendation.

SKILLS

Python, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Networkx, Grakn graph database, Seaborn, PySpark, JavaScript, AngularJS

Professional EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. - System Engineer

January 2017 - Present

- Proposed multiple business solutions as a part of job role and helped developing solution for them.
- Implemented Named Entity Recognition using LSTM algorithm with Tensorflow
- Recommendation problems using NetworkX and experience working in Grakn graph database.
- Tag Extraction using LDA, POS, and from front-end using JavaScript
- Datasets preparation and implementation of classification and document similarity problems
- Relevant search implementation for assets using PostgreSQL.
- Expert ranking for associates.

FusionCharts Technologies Pvt. Ltd., - JS Developer

July 2016 - December 2016

• Adding new functionalities to different type of charts and creating new charts based on company requirements. Implementations were made using maths, data structure with JavaScript.

Shoes on loose, - Python Developer Intern

October 2015 - November 2015

- Hobby Projects Machine Learning Hackathons
 - Predict Hospital stay duration for COVID patients using CatBoost, GridSearchCV Rank: 142 / 19Kc
 - Predict Future Sales using XGBRegressor Rank: 277 / 8K
 - Twitter Sentiment Analysis using LSTM Rank : 416 / 15K ♂
 - BigMart Sales Prediction using StackingCVRegressor Rank: 1726 / 32K
 - Time Series Forecasting of JetRail passengers using Prophet, Holt's Winter, Sarimax Rank: 399 / 19KC
 - Exam Preparation Online (epon.in) 2 An online portal to simplify the email digest for their daily learning activities on machine learning, sports and technology. It also features interview experiences and success stories in simplified format.
 - Filter out blog links from mail contents and broadcast relevant contents via website and chrome extension.
 - Extract text using tesseract from Images of question papers and segregate them to individual questions
 - Extract questions from interview experiences, identify unique questions using XGBoost ML algorithm and classify them to corresponding subjects using Ensemble Classification algorithm. Dataset preparation required for performing Ensemble Classification method.
 - Interview experiences to display only required information like suggestions, technical questions, others...
 - 200+ Subscribers, 300+ monthly visits, 2K unique visits before interviews, 1.3K FB likes
 - Google Search Recommendation 2 Chrome extension to track online activity of user. Visual representation of online activity through charts and recommended links in Google search page based on their past activities.

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning

- Natural Language Processing in TensorFlow &
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- TCS Machine Learning E2 competency ♂
- Basic Sentiment Analysis with TensorFlow ♂
- Compare Stock Returns with Google Sheets ♂
- Data Analysis Using Pyspark ♂
- Exploratory Data Analysis with Seaborn
- Predict Future Product Prices Using Facebook Prophet &
- The Data Scientists Toolbox by Johns Hopkins University
- Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach by University of Washington

EDUCATION

Institute of Engineering & Management, Kolkata, B.Tech., (DGPA): 8.42 / 10